SHELBY THOMAS

UI/UX Designer

Higher education professional turned UX/UI designer with experience working with diverse populations. Bringing curiosity, thoughtfulness, and problem-solving skills to the design process to produce beautiful and effective user-centered designs with the ultimate goal of improving user quality of life.

CONTACT

shelbythomas253@gmail.com shelbythomas.me 858-395-5317 Costa Mesa, California

SKILLS

Design Thinking

User Research

User Personas

User Flows

Usability Testing

Wireframing

Visual Design

Responsive Design

Prototyping

Mockups

TOOLS

Sketch

Figma

Balsamiq

InVision

Flinto

Salesforce

EDUCATION

UI Design Certification

Career Foundry | Jan. 2020 - Aug. 2020

- Career Foundry's UI Design Program is a 9 month, 500+ hour intensive program that spanned from visual design principles, color theory, and grids to wireframing, prototyping, responsive design, and more.
- Produced several pixel-perfect mockups including native apps and responsive web apps

B.A. Human Development, Minor in Child Development

California State University, Long Beach | May 2012 - Dec. 2015

WORK EXPERIENCE

Simon Family Foundation

Senior Program Coordinator | Jan. 2019 - Present

- Streamlined scholarship funding process for 350+ students resulting in optimized staff time
- Supported management of Salesforce; including training team members and executing changes
- Assisted class of 2020 caseload (13 seniors) in receiving over \$300,000 in grants & scholarships

Program Coordinator | Nov. 2016 -Jan. 2019

- Executed curriculum and events to increase college knowledge and leadership skills of first-generation, lowincome high school students
- Managed caseload of 32 high school students and 60+ college students
- Maintained professional relationship with program's partner high school contacts

DeVry University

Operations Support Coordinator I | Jan. 2016 - Nov. 2016

- · Guided federal work-study students in daily job duties
- · Aided in planning and implementing campus events
- Resolved student issues through effective communication and problem solving